

**Shweta Agarwal** 

E-mail: agshweta@yahoo.com

Cell: 77713173

#### TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Total Ten years of extensive experience in Information Technology in Botswana and India, covering functional and technical aspects. Possess excellent skills in Software Engineering, Management Information System (MIS), System analysis and design. Developed strong interpersonal, communication and analytical skills. Worked in team environment emphasizing organizational goals. Ability to learn and adapt to new technologies/environments. To be associated with a progressing organization, as an OCP, contributing my best at all times and excelling all endeavors, where my attributes and abilities are enriched and enhanced.

## **EDUCATION:**

Oracle Certified Professional (OCP) in development track.

Advanced Diploma in Software Engineering from Aptech Computer Education

(India). (Main Languages: Oracle, C++, Unix, and FoxPro).

*Year*: 1995 – 1998 *Grade*: Distinction

#### **Bachelors Degree in Science**

University: Rohilkhand University, Bareilly, India

*Year*: 1993 – 1996 *Division*: First

Additional knowledge: HTML and Web Designing.

### SPECIAL ACHIEVEMENTS

Stood seventh in Year III (Final Year) of Advanced Diploma from Aptech all India.

Stood second in Year III (Final Year) of Advanced Diploma from Aptech in Northern Zone of India.

#### **EXPERIENCES:**

# **JANUARY 2009 TO DATE**

Independent Technical Consultant

During this period, I worked as an independent consultant and handled a number of applications in asset management, wealth management and stock broking industry. These applications were based on SQL & Oracle.

#### **JULY 2007 TO MARCH 2008**

Software Application and Information Solutions (Pty) Ltd, Gaborone - Trainee

## BOTSWANA INSURANCE FUND MANAGEMENT

- Worked on Unitisation System
- Support Pension Administration System according to client's requirements
- Modifying and creating new FSG reports in Oracle Apps according to client's requirements

### NATIONAL DEVELOPMENT BANK

- Developed Management report using Oracle Discoverer according to the client's specifications with Oracle Apps Interface
- Comparing two systems (Bank Master and Oracle) for each user's account to check the balances in their account are same. If not, then finding the problem and fixing it.
- Developed reports using Oracle Report Builder to show difference in balances comparing both systems (Bank Master and Oracle).
- Developed reports and forms using Forms and Reports 6i.
- Worked on PL/SQL.

# **BOTSWANA MEAT COMMISSION**

• Modified the current system (Direct Cattle Purchase) according to their requirements that includes modifications of existing tables, forms, reports, functions and development of new tables, forms, reports and functions using Oracle Form Builder and Oracle Report Builder.

**IN-HOUSE PROJECT** 

- Timesheet Management System Designing & development of database, forms and reports to keep track of employee's timesheets, number of chargeable hours worked on each project at each client and generate job card, invoices for the client.
- Marketing System Designing & development of database, forms and reports to keep track of contact lists, appointments and function as a reminding tool for all future appointments.
- Mmegi Sales Tracking System Designing & development of database, forms and reports for keeping track of the sales in different outlets for Mmegi newspaper, Gaborone

# JANUARY 2003 TO DECEMBER 2003 Corp Consult (Pty) Ltd, Gaborone - *Trainee*

- Corp Libris Complete maintenance of library operations in a school for Senior and Junior Secondary Schools
- Contact Management Database designing and development for the maintenance of organization contacts for African Comprehensive HIV/AIDS Partnership (ACHAP)
- IT Help Desk System Simplifying the process of sending requests to the admin and receiving the solutions for Botswana Insurance Fund Management, Gaborone
- Loan Management System Designing and developing a customized software to keep track of loans issued, loans received and closed, payments due, interest calculation, number of instalment calculation etc.
- Corp Bursar Designing and developing a software for the maintenance of school accounting system for Senior and Junior Secondary Schools

#### OCTOBER 1999 TO SEPTEMBER 2002

Gaborone Institute of Professional Studies – Aptech Computer Education (Gaborone) – Faculty for semester courses

Liasing with the Head Office in India for the arrangements of examination, certificates. Helping students in developing project in Visual Basic, Oracle and Web Designing

Main subjects taught: Visual Basic, FoxPro, C, C++ Oracle, and Web Designing

# May 1997 to May 1999 Aptech Computer Eduaction – Bareilly (India) – Faculty for semester courses

Assisting students in developing projects in Visual Basic, FoxPro and Oracle

Main subjects taught: Visual Basic, FoxPro, C, and C++ and Oracle